--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.cmct.tv
影片压制：死亡骑士　字幕调校：死亡骑士　招募Q号：76846146
源字幕翻译：深影字幕组
片名：精灵旅社
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome! Welcome!
恭喜 德古
Congrats, Drac.
天呐 大家都来了
Holy smokes, everybody's here.
洛克伦夫妇 新郎的父母 携其家人
Mr. and Mrs. Loughran, the parents of the groom, and family.
- 爸爸 妈妈 - 乔尼
- Mom and Dad! - Johnny!
真不敢相信你们都来了
I can't believe you're all here.
嗷 耶 耶 耶
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah!
我的女伴是不是超火辣
Yo, how hot is my date?
火辣爆了
So hot. Wow.
我的女伴是不是也超火辣
How 'bout how hot mine is?
你带了女伴
You got a date?
是啊 她隐身了 所以你们看不见她
Yeah. She's invisible. That's why you can't see her.
哦对 这就是从"加拿大"来的那个吗
Oh, right. This is the one from "Canada"?
婚礼要开始了
Wedding's starting.
真棒
Great.
对 说得太对了 马蒂
True. So true, Marty.
太贴心了
Aw. How sweet.
天啊 看看你
Oh, my. Look at you.
我的天呐
Oh, my gosh.
一切都如你的意吗 我的小毒果儿
Is it everything you wanted, my little poisonberry?
是的 爸爸
Oh, it is, Daddy.
不过瓦拉德爷爷在哪呢
Except where's Grandpa Vlad?
亲爱的 你爷爷可接受不了你们结婚
Honey, your gramps would not have been cool with this.
他很老派的
He's old-school.
我们怎么知道 如果他能见见乔尼
How do we know? If he could just meet Johnny...
他会吃了他的
He would have eaten him.
他不像你的时髦老爹这么开明
He's not as enlightened as your hip Daddy.
那么 你真的能接受他不是怪物吗
So, you're really okay with him not being a monster?
人类 怪物 独角兽 只要你幸福就好
Human, monster, unicorn, as long as you're happy.
谢谢 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
你将永远是我的白月光
∮ And you'll always be my moonlight ∮
但如今你乘爱的翅膀高飞
∮ But now on wings of love you soar ∮
现在你是乔尼的妻子
∮ Now that you're Johnny's girl ∮
乔尼的妻子
∮ Johnny's girl ∮
也还是爸爸的乖女儿
∮ And kind of Daddy's, too ∮
你妈妈肯定会很高兴的
∮ Your mom would be so happy ∮
因为她一直明白
∮ 'Cause she always knew ∮
爱将为你们的美满幸福开路
∮ Love is making room for all the best in you? ∮
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
你好 两位
Oh, hey, guys!
托德 休息一下
Todd, take a break.
有事吗
So, what's up?
梅菲丝想问问你想不想飞出去兜兜风
Mavis was wondering if maybe you wanted to go for a fly.
我们好久没那样啦 有什么特殊原因吗
Oh. We haven't done that in forever. Any special reason?
什么特殊原因都没有
No special reason at all.
是吧 梅
Right, Mavey?
他打的什么主意
What's his deal?
他只是在犯傻啦
He's silly.
这么一个美好的夜晚
It's just a beautiful night, and...
好吧 如果你不想出去的话
Well, if you don't want to...
不不 你开玩笑吗
No, no! Are you kidding?
为了和你飞一圈让我吃一桶大蒜都情愿
I would eat a bucket of garlic to fly with you.
宝贝 看那些毛茸茸的云朵
Oh, honey, look at those fluffy clouds.
记得你小时候我们玩的游戏吗
Remember what we played when you were little?
捉迷藏的游戏
Hide and go seek sharp objects?
好吧 和往常一样捉迷藏
Okay. Regular hide and go seek.
你在哪
Where are you?
小蝙蝠
Honeybat!
小梅
Mavey!
小蝙蝠
Honeybat!
我会找到你的
I'm gonna get you.
亲爱的 你还好吧
Honey? Are you okay?
没事 只是我怀孕了
Yes. It's just a little harder
所以有点喘不上气
to catch my breath since I'm pregnant.
是的 我想确实有点
Yes, well, I guess that would make it more...
什么
What?
我要当外公了
I'm gonna be a Grandpa!
而我要当爸爸了
And I'm gonna be a Dad!
只因你是爹地的小姑娘 或者小子
∮ 'Cause you're Daddy's girl, or boy ∮
爹地的小姑娘 或者小子
∮ Daddy's girl, or boy ∮
我又饿了 亲爱的
I'm hungry again, honey.
你能不能给我拿点凤尾鱼冰激凌
Can you get me some ice cream with anchovies?
不不不 可不能想吃什么就吃什么
No, no, no. You mustn't give in to your cravings.
那对宝宝不好
It's not good for the baby.
你需要吃多点蜘蛛
You need to increase your spider intake,
这样他才能更好的爬上天花板
so he'll be able to climb ceilings properly.
还要喝很多羊胆汁
And eat lots of sheep bile.
我爱你 爸爸 可是我们不知道
I love you, Dad, but we don't even know
这孩子是不是吸血鬼
if the kid's gonna be a vampire.
如果宝宝能像乔尼一样是普通人类 我会很开心的
I'd be thrilled if the baby's human-y, just like Johnny.
"普通人类" 你可是有着千年德古拉基因
"Human-y." With thousands of years of Dracula genes.
绝对不可能
Not gonna happen.
只要宝宝是健康的
As long as the baby's healthy.
当然 一个健康的小吸血鬼
Of course. A healthy little vampire.
或是人类
Or human.
是 一个能像蝙蝠一样飞翔的人类
Yes, a human who can fly as a bat.
来吧 喝点怪物球球汤
Here. Just have some monster ball soup.
这可是你妈妈的食谱哦
It's your mommy's recipe.
谢谢 爸爸
Thank you, Dad.
和小时候你给我做的一样 我的最爱
Just like you made it when I was a kid. My favorite.
对不起
Sorry.
先生 只有孩子的生父才能进入产房
Sir, only the father is allowed in the delivery room.
真的吗 我是说 好吧
Really? I mean, okay.
他算是家人了 我猜
He's the family, I guess.
快看 是个男孩 是个男孩
Oh, look! It's a boy! It's a boy!
德古拉的血脉得以延续了
The Dracula bloodline carries on!
只要我在这 没人能伤害你
No one will ever harm you as long as I'm here,
我的小魔狗
my little devil dog.
爸爸 我能抱抱孩子吗
Dad, can I hold my baby?
如果我是你爸爸 我会答应的
If I were Dad, I'd say yes.
可我是护士 弗朗辛
But I'm the nurse, Francine.
不过还是给你吧
Here you go anyway.
我错了
My bad.
小丹尼斯现在一岁了
Little Dennis is a year old now. Wow!
干得漂亮 可爱的孩子
Nice. Yeah. Cute kid.
好了 开礼物时间 大伙们
Okay, time for presents, guys.
我们让这小子大吃一惊吧
All right! Let's do this boy up!
看看我送给他的 闪瞎你们狗眼
Check out what I got him. Bling!
是受过诅咒的吗
Is it cursed?
超级受诅咒 我只送最好的
Super cursed. Only the best.
直接从埃及地下墓室送来的
Straight from the crypt.
他才刚开始走路 所以那东西对他可能太重了
He's just starting to walk, so maybe it's heavier than...
你没事的 丹尼索维奇
Oh. You're okay, Denisovich.
他的名字是丹尼斯 以我父亲命名的
His name is Dennis. Named after my father.
那不是他的吸血鬼名字
It's not his vampire name.
我的小丹尼索维奇-小小索维奇
My little Denisovichy-weesovichy.
你确定他是吸血鬼吗
Are we sure he's a vampire?
我是说 倒也不是说不好
I mean, not that it's a bad thing,
但难道他不是应该有你们的尖牙和苍白肤色吗
but shouldn't he have fangs and that pasty skin you guys have?
理论上说 你得等到五岁才会长出吸血鬼尖牙
Technically, you have until you're five to get your vampire fangs.
他会长出尖牙的 他是德古拉家的人
Oh, he'll get his fangs. He's a Dracula.
他也有一半洛克伦血统
He's also half Loughran.
也许他在我们住的地方生活更好 那里有更多人类
Maybe he'd be better off where we live. There's more humans there.
什么 看看他和小狼崽们玩得有多开心
What? Look how well he's playing with the wolf pups.
我们有份礼物 希望你能收下
We have a present. I hope it's acceptable.
"我的第一个断头台"
"My first guillotine."
非常具有教育意义 送得好 弗兰克
Very educational. Well played, Frank.
很棒 谢谢 我们得要给它儿童防护一下
It's great. Thank you. We just have to baby-proof that.
乔尼 你知道你把橡胶防护放哪了吗
Johnny, do you know where you put the rubber guards?
给断头台装儿童防护
Baby-proofing a guillotine?
大不了把手指切了 那可是乐趣的一部分
So you cut your finger off. It's part of the fun.
她让我把整个旅馆都装了儿童防护
She made me baby-proof the whole hotel.
某人保护过度了
Someone's overprotective.
乔尼 快来
Johnny! Come quick!
什么事 他还好吗
What's up? He's okay?
丹尼斯刚说了他的第一个词
Dennis said his first word!
他说了
He did?
来吧 亲爱的 再说一次
Come on, honey. Say it again.
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
我可不说 "巴拉 巴拉巴拉"
I don't say, "bleh, bleh-bleh."
我们没说你说啊
We didn't say you did.
那他从哪学来的
Then where did he get that?
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
也许你有时候会这么说
Well, maybe sometimes you say it.
我只有形容我不说的情况下才会说
I only say it when I say I don't say it!
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
好吧 小屁孩 我们知道了 你会说话了
Okay, kid. We get it. You can talk.
丹尼索维奇
Denisovich.
爸爸
Dad.
只是检查有没有蛀牙
Just checking for cavities.
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
原来是你
It was you!
我的天啊 伦纳德
Oh, my goodness, Leonard.
如果你真长得那么丑
If you really looked that hideous,
我想我可能没法和你一起出去玩了
I don't think I could hang out with you.
伙计们 都在搞什么呢
Guys, what's the deal?
你们这是开派对吗 快接电话
Is this a party? Pick up a phone.
我才不在乎乔尼说的是不是这个酷应用乔尼在这还是新人
I don't care if Johnny said it's a "cool app." Johnny's still new here.
好了 浆糊脑 你有没有打电话给精灵人订灵车
Now, porridge head, did you call a hearse for the Gremlinbergs?
没有 你又在看你的脸书了
No, you're checking your Facebook page. Again.
德古 我和大家说了社交媒体
Drac, I told the guys social media
是宣传旅馆的最佳方式
is the best way to promote the hotel.
对吗 克利夫顿
Right, Clifton?
那么 德古 我想和你谈谈我的一些想法
So, Drac, I wanted to go through some thoughts I had,
作为你新上任的人类关系协调助手
as your new human relations coordinating co-assistant.
当然 这是一份真的工作
Sure. It's a real job.
可不是用来哄梅菲丝开心的 好让你永远不离开这里
Not a cheap excuse to keep Mavis happy, so you never leave here.
好吧 那么 我在想
Right. So, I was thinking,
既然现在这里有了这么多人类 也许我们应该升级一下表演
since we have so many humans now, maybe update some of the acts?
或许该请个魔术师
Like, maybe the magician?
三眼哈里有什么不好
What's wrong with Harry three-eye?
可他对人类来说有点老派了
Well, he might be a little old-school for the humans.
告诉我 先生 你的牌是什么
Tell me, sir, what was your card?
黑桃三
The three of spades?
这是你的牌吗 我的朋友
Is this your card, my friend?
哇哦
Whoa!
不 哈里好得很
No, Harry's great.
观众跟不上潮流不能怪哈里
Can't blame Harry for the crowd not being hip.
好吧 那韦恩呢
Okay, what about Wayne?
韦恩 你是不是疯了 他是我铁哥们
Wayne? Are you nuts? He's my boy.
那除了网球 让他干点别的吧
Then maybe something other than tennis?
好 所以 你想要做的是
Okay, so, what you wanna do
击球时把球拍抬起 这样你就能打出漂亮的上旋球
is lift the racket right on impact, so you get that nice top spin.
来一个球试试
Try and hit one.
那是什么 什么声音 它在我身上
What is that? What's the noise? It's on me!
是我给你买的手机
It's just the cell phone I got you.
克利夫顿给你发了短信 好让你练习怎么回信息
Clifton's sending you a text so you can practice how to write back.
什么鬼… 根本没用
What the... It's not doing it.
我来吧
I got it.
亲爱的德古 嘎啦嘎啦嘎啦
dear drac gar ugha gjergh arggh grgrgrhgr
现在你就能给克利夫顿回短信了
Now you can text Clifton.
好吧 好吧
All right, fine.
怎么弄这个
How do you do this?
可能是你的指甲
Maybe it's your fingernails.
很容易的 看吧 我来给梅菲丝发短信
It's easy. Look. I'll text Mavis.
约会之夜好期待
Psyched for date night.
看到没 现在你看 她回复我了
See? And now look, she texted right back.
"得取消了 不能丢下丹尼斯"
"Gotta cancel. Can't leave Dennis."
好吧
Okay.
我们是不是再也不能独处了
Are we never allowed to be alone again?
我也需要感受被人关爱
I need to feel loved, too.
发送
And send.
够了 我只学会你真窝囊这件事
Okay. All that taught me is that you're pathetic.
知道了 也许你应该来个蓝牙
Yeah, got it. Maybe you should just get Bluetooth.
好吧 蓝牙 过来
Okay. Blue tooth, come over here.
那 现在呢
So, now what?
快起床啦 我的丹尼索维奇
Rise and shine, my Denisovich.
你好 外公
Hi, Papa.
你好 我的小恶魔 有没有做甜蜜的噩梦呢
Hello, my little devil. Did you have sweet nightmares?
有呢 我梦见我遇到了剑龙
Uh-huh. I dreamed that I saw a stegosaurus.
那有没有喝它的血
Oh... and were you drinking his blood?
没有
No.
就先不管它了
Just throwing it out there.
嗨 你想不想做点很酷的事
Hey! You want to do something cool?
好耶
Yeah!
接下来我要教你怎么变成蝙蝠 像我这样
I'm going to teach you how to turn into a bat. Like me.
- 看到没 - 酷
- See? - Cool.
是的 酷 正如我说的那样
Yes! Cool, like I said.
现在你来试试
Now you try.
我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat.
我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat. I'm a bat. I'm a bat.
我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat.
我意思是 一只真正的蝙蝠
I mean, a real bat.
我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat!
丹尼索维奇 深吸一口气 你真的可以变成蝙蝠
Denisovich. Take a breath. You can really turn into a bat.
试试 想想蝙蝠
Try. Feel the bat.
不是公鸡啦
Not a chicken.
那是什么 机械舞吗
What's that? The electric boogaloo?
如果我跳舞给你看 你会认真试着飞一下吗
If I show you I can bust a move, will you try to fly, then?
好啊
Uh-huh.
爸爸 为什么你们在跳舞
Dad? Why are you guys dancing?
他是在梦游跳舞
Uh, he was sleep-dancing.
来吧 宝贝 上床睡觉了
Come on, sweetie. Back to bed.
上床睡觉？已经过了晚上八点了
"Back to bed"? It's already after 8:00 P.M.
你不记得新的睡眠时间表了吗
Don't you remember the new sleep schedule?
他每天都要去人类班级上半天课
He's going to human classes half the day.
如果他今晚能睡到凌晨两点 对他身体会大有益处的
If he could just sleep till 2:00 A.M. tonight, it'd be so great for him.
但是 宝贝 韦恩的六个小狼崽子
But, honeydeath, six of Wayne's wolf pups
今晚要办生日派对
are having a birthday party tonight.
你可不想让他错过吧
You wouldn't want him to miss that.
爸爸 我很爱那些小狼崽 但他们对丹尼斯有点太粗暴了
Dad, I love the wolf pups, but they're a little too rough for Dennis.
"太粗暴"
"Too rough"?
你没注意到吗 丹尼斯不一样
Haven't you noticed? Dennis is different.
你在说什么 丹尼索维奇不应该和怪物们在一起玩吗
What are you saying? Denisovich shouldn't be around monsters?
- 我爱怪物们 视频 视频 - 哈
- I love monsters! Video! Video! - Ha!
你想给德古外公看你的怪物视频吗
Oh, you wanna show Papa Drac your monster video?
是的
Yeah!
谁是最酷的怪物
Who's the coolest monster?
凯蒂
Kakie!
耶 凯蒂是快乐怪物
Wee! Kakie one happy monster!
凯蒂爱吃蛋糕 好美味
Kakie love cake! Yummy!
肚子痛痛
Tummy get a tummyache.
喔 喔 喔 这怎么能算怪物
Whoa, whoa, whoa. How is that a monster?
吃点蛋糕吧 乌兹拉粑粑
Have some cake, wuzzlelumplebum.
记住 孩子们 真正的怪物总是会分享
Remember, kids, a real monster always shares.
"分享" 是的 当我想到怪物的时候 我想到的却是"分享"
"Shares"? Yes! When I think monsters, I think "shares."
现在 让我告诉你什么才是真正的怪物 丹尼索维奇
Now, let me tell you what a real monster is, Denisovich.
爸爸 拜托了 严格来说他已经五岁了 不要逼他了
Dad, please. He's practically five already. Don't force it.
慢点吃 乌兹拉粑粑
Slow down, wuzzlelumplebum.
一闪一闪亮晶晶 满天都是小星星
∮ Twinkle, Twinkle, little star how I wonder ∮
妈妈 我已经不是听摇篮曲的年龄了
Mommy, I'm too old for lullabies.
什么 这歌可不是那么唱的
What? That's not how that one goes.
大多数人都是这么唱的
This is the way most people sing it.
"大多数人"？这么唱有什么错
"Most people"? What's wrong with...
一喊一叫惨兮兮
∮ Suffer, suffer, scream in pain ∮
满天都是脑出血
∮ Blood is spilling from your brain? ∮
- 爸爸 - 来吧 你知道我是怎么跟你唱的
- Daddy. - Come on. You know how I sang it to you.
僵尸咬你爆血浆
∮ Zombies gnaw you like a plum ∮
刺耳哭喊你投降
∮ Piercing cries and you succumb ∮
一喊一叫惨兮兮
∮ Suffer, suffer, scream in pain ∮
你将永远没气息
∮ You will never breathe again? ∮
仍然管用
Still works.
生日快乐 沃利 威尔逊
Happy birthday, Wally, Wilson,
乌皮 韦伦 韦皮还有万娅
Whoopi, Waylon, Weepy and Wanye.
丹尼索维奇 我的大男孩 你来了
Denisovich! My big boy! You made it!
我想了想之前你说过的话 爸爸
I thought about what you said, Dad.
也许我是有点保护过度了
Maybe I was being a little overprotective.
谢谢 棺材小蛋糕
Thank you, coffin cake.
丹尼斯 命中注定我爱你
Dennis! I love you! Zing!
嗨 温妮
Hi, Winnie.
我就喜欢你草莓味的卷头发 命中注定 命中注定
I just love your yummy strawberry locks! Zing, zing!
温妮 给他点空间 抱歉 梅菲丝
Winnie. Give him his space, hon. I'm sorry, Mavis.
没关系 汪妲婶婶 他们只是闹着玩
It's okay, aunt Wanda. They're just playing.
天呐 地狱边境 我以前好爱这个游戏
Holy rabies! Limbo? I used to love that game!
去玩吧 小梅
Get in there, Mavey.
真的吗 可我现在已身为人母了
Really? But I'm a parent now.
给他们点厉害看看
Show 'em how it's done.
好吧 好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay, okay.
不会吧 一个皮纳塔
No way! A pinata?
噢 梅菲丝亲爱的 那个待会再玩
Oh, Mavis, honey. That's for later.
我们不想让小崽子们吃太多
We don't want the pups to have too much...
糖果
Candy!
糖分
Sugar.
对不起 是我引起的吗
I'm sorry. Did I start all that?
别担心 他们管它叫窝可是有原因的
Don't worry. There's a reason they call it a litter.
丹尼斯 你还好吗
Dennis! Are you okay?
我捡到一颗糖
I got a candy.
看 你的牙掉了
Look! Your tooth came out.
你和我开玩笑吗 他的牙被撞掉了
Are you kidding me? He got his tooth knocked out?
哦是的 没错 尖牙要出来了
Oh, yes, indeed. Here comes the fang.
爸爸 他的乳牙不是尖牙 那这颗又怎么会是
Dad. His baby tooth wasn't a fang. Why would this one be?
他不是怪物
He's not a monster.
太阳就要出来了 我们要送他去上课了
The sun's gonna come out soon, and we gotta get to his classes.
我们这里的课程有什么不好 比如儿童瑜伽
What's wrong with the classes we have here? Like the kids' yoga?
瑜伽
Yoga!
这里是丹尼索维奇的家
This is Denisovich's home.
我不知道 爸爸
I don't know, Dad.
你不知道什么
What don't you know?
我们一直在谈搬家的事
Well, we've been talking about moving.
对丹尼斯更安全的地方
Somewhere safer for Dennis.
或许是乔尼在加利福尼亚长大的地方
Maybe where Johnny grew up in California.
我很抱歉 但你不能让事物按照不属于他们的方式生存
I'm sorry, but you can't just make somebody something they're not.
来吧 亲爱的 我们要走了
Come on, honey. We have to go.
命中注定
Zing, zing?
小梅 等等 你不能这样
Mavey, wait. You can't mean that.
你怂恿她的 对吧 搬家
You're in on this? The leaving?
呃… 不完全是
Uh... It's not definite at all.
她只是有谈过这件事
It's just something she's definitely talking about,
但直到我们真正决定下来 都是不确定的
but until we do it, it's not definitized.
他刚才是用鸟食裹住我了吗
Did he just cover me with birdseed?
好吧 他裹住我了
Yeah, he covered me.
爸爸 那不是尖牙
Dad, it's not a fang.
爸爸 我不确定这对丹尼斯来说是不是个好地方
Dad, I don't know if it's the right place for Dennis.
对吧乔尼
Right, Johnny?
老伙计 不是我的主意 是小梅的
Oh, hey, dudeman. It's not me. It's Mavey.
嘿 老伙计我什么也不敢说
Hey, dudeman. I'm afraid to say anything.
嘿 老伙计 我是老伙计
Hey, dudeman. I'm a dudeman!
德古 你在跟谁说话
Uh, Drac? Who you talkin' to?
请勿打扰 伯爵正在发牢骚呢
Do not disturb. The count's wiggin' out in here.
你在发什么牢骚啊 德古
What are you wiggin' out about, Drac?
还不是那些孩子 小梅说她想要搬走
The kids. Mavey wavey's saying she wants to leave.
她想搬走 那乔尼怎么办 他可不想走
She wants to leave? What about Johnny? He doesn't wanna go.
他为了丹尼斯正在努力让旅社更加人类化
He's making the hotel more human-y for Dennis.
你知道的 因为他不是怪物
You know, seeing that he isn't a monster.
他就是个怪物
He is a monster!
他只是还没发育 尖牙长得慢
He's just a late fanger.
我可以当一只手模
And I could be a hand model.
闭嘴 都是那些人类的东西
Shut up! It's all that human-y stuff
给可怜的丹尼索维奇造成了困扰
that's confusing poor Denisovich.
所以或许你该让那孩子多接触点怪物的东西
So maybe you gotta get the kid around more monster-y things. Ooh!
我需要一件披风
Oh, I need a cape.
我办不到 她总是待在他身边 防范着我
I can't. She's always around, checking up on me.
伙计 要是你们可以单独呆会的话
Man, if you could just get some alone time.
等等 那也是乔尼想要的
Wait a minute. That's what Johnny wants, too.
和梅菲丝的两人世界
Alone time with Mavis.
他们结婚以前
Have they even had a vacation
有去旅行过吗
since before they were married?
他们马上就要去了 我们也是 弗兰克 你是个天才
They're going to now. And so are we. Frank, you're a genius.
我们要带丹尼索维奇去以前我们常去的地方
We'll take Denisovich to all our old haunts.
我们给他展示一下我们的绝技
Each of us will show him our skills.
教他怎么做一个怪物
Teach him how to be a monster.
这样他很快就会长出獠牙了
And he'll be fanging it up in no time.
那男孩下星期就满五岁了
Boy turns five next week.
如果他在生日那天没变成吸血鬼 那就永远不可能了
If he's not a vampire by his birthday, it ain't happenin'.
噢 一定会变的 宝贝
Oh, it ain't ain't happening, baby.
他只是需要花时间和他的鬼公在一起
All he needs is time with his vampa.
什么鬼公
"Vampa"?
吸血鬼外公
Vampire Grandpa.
拜托 伙计 这很明显好吗
Come on, man. That's obvious.
乔尼 出来
Johnny. Come outside.
什么 谁在外面
What? Who is it?
你岳父大人 我得和你谈谈
It's your father-in-law. I need to talk to you.
怎么了
What's up?
我来弄走他们 抱歉
Let me get rid of them. Sorry.
没关系 我还挺喜欢它们围着我转的
No problem-o. I was kinda diggin' the attention.
它们能留下来吗 我觉得它们还没有准备好离开
Can they stay? I don't think they're ready to leave yet.
走吧 找你们的妈妈去
Come on. Go to your mother.
听着 你想要留下来 对吧
Look, you want to stay here, right?
当然
Of course.
这是第一个我可以完全做自己的地方
This is the first place where I can really be myself.
自从他们发明了芝心匹萨后 我从来没有这么充满活力过
I haven't felt this alive since they invented stuffed-crust pizza.
好吧 那我们就有事情要做了 听着 我有个计划
Well, then, we've got some work to do. Okay, so here's the plan.
或许带她回你家是个好主意
Maybe it's a good idea to take her to your hometown.
但是记住
But remember...
把牛油果切成片给他吃 燕麦片还有杏仁
So, it's sliced avocado, rolled oats with apricot,
每次洗完澡要抹强生的润肤乳
the aveeno moisturizer after every bath.
换睡衣前在牙齿上抹点乳木果油
And then the shea butter on his tush before his pjs
然后给他读幼儿识字发音书的时候
and then 20 minutes with the nebulizer
同时用喷雾剂喷二十分钟
while I read his learning factory phonics book to him.
带小孩很辛苦 爸爸 我们可以带上丹尼斯的
It's asking a lot, Dad. We could just take Dennis with us.
什么 别开玩笑了 你要打破他的生活规律吗
What? Are you kidding me? And get him off his routine?
不 不 不
No, no, no.
你们俩去加利福尼亚好好玩
You kids go to California,
看看那里适不适合丹尼索维奇的成长
and see if it's the right place to raise Denisovich.
你记得怎么视频通话吧
And you remember how to video chat?
记得 记得 用手机按键真的让我痛苦不堪
Yes, yes. With the phone and the buttons and the agony.
谢谢你这么善解人意 爸爸 我知道你会好好保护他的
Thanks for being so understanding, Dad. I know you'll keep him safe.
当然了 小梅 以被木桩穿心发誓 我会好好保护他的
Of course, Mavey. Stake my heart and hope to die.
我会很想他的
I'm just gonna miss him so much.
我爱你 丹尼斯
I love you, Dennis.
我也爱你 妈咪
I love you, mommy.
每晚睡前我都会跟他讲你小时候的故事
I'll tell him Mavey Wavey stories every night before bed.
你是最棒的 我爱你 爸爸
You're the best. I love you, Dad.
我会想你们的 你们都是我的家人
Gonna miss all you guys. You're all my family.
爱你哦 德古
Love you, Drac.
我也爱… 你
Yes. I love you, too.
记住我们的计划 让她分心 快乐至上
Now, remember the plan. Just keep her distracted and happy.
- 但别太高兴了 明白吗 - 明白
- But not too happy, capisce? - Got it.
行动"让她分心 快乐至上"
Operation "just keep her distracted and happy,
"但别太高兴了 明白吗" 现在开始 酷炫吧
"but not too happy, capisce, " starts now. Cool?
在外面要多微笑
Smiling on the outside.
你可以抱抱我的背包吗
Will you hug my backpack?
不
No.
要上床睡觉了
Back to bed.
好的 我们都要回床上去了 我们都爱床
Ah, yes, we'll get to the bed. We all love the bed.
但我们得先完成一件事
But we're just gonna do one thing first.
我们去的地方是夏天吗
Is it shorts weather where we're going?
天啊 我希望不是 我的身材还没准备好穿泳衣
Jeez. I hope not. My body isn't swimsuit-ready yet.
随便吧 格里芬在哪里
Whatever. Where's Griffin?
能等等我吗 我要跟艾米莉道别
Hey, can I have a second? I'm just saying goodbye to Emily.
噢 兄弟
Oh, brother.
我会想念你的
I'm gonna miss you so much.
你得坚强一点 亲爱的
You know, you have to be strong, honey.
因为我们是坚不可摧的
Because what we have is unbreakable.
宝贝 别哭 大家都看着呢
Babe, don't cry. Everyone's looking.
够了 我要去揭穿他
Okay, I gotta call him on this.
就让他继续演 别管他
Just let him play it out, get it over with.
好了 你们这对小情侣 快把香槟喝了 我们要出发了
Okay, you two lovebirds. Drink your champagne and let's get going.
不 哎 好吧
Oh, yeah. No, sure. Okay.
干杯 宝贝
Cheers, babe.
噢 你这个笨蛋
Oh. You klutz.
我们不能发表任何意见吗
We can't say nothin' about this?
不 我们没有时间来反驳他了
No. We don't have time for zingers.
这个该死的安全带应该怎么系啊
How do you click in the stupid car seat?
你该剪指甲了 伙计
You gotta cut those nails, man.
我们都用胶带来绑我们的小孩
We just strap our kids down with duct tape.
他在这里干什么
What's he doing here?
我跟他说他可以一起来 他从来没踏出过旅社一步
I told him he could come. He's never been outside the hotel.
鼻涕虫 这里没空位了 抱歉伙计
Blobby, there's no room. Sorry, man.
看 还是有位置的
Yeah, that ain't happenin'.
好吧 带上这个无赖 我们快走吧
Fine, put him on the rascal. Let's just get going.
我们要去哪里啊 德古外公
Where are we going, Papa Drac?
丹尼索维奇 我们要去大冒险
Oh, Denisovich, we're going to have an adventure.
一场怪物大冒险
A monster-y adventure.
棒耶 怪物 我们要去吃蛋糕啦
Yay! Monsters! We're gonna eat cake.
他说什么
What did he say?
不 这趟怪物之旅可没有蛋糕
No. No cake on this monster trip.
没有蛋糕 因为凯蒂说过"蛋糕吃多了肚肚痛"
No cake, cebause Kakie says, "too much cake makes tummy ache."
耶
Yay!
"怪物永远都会分享"
"A monster always shares."
我们可能需要不止一周的时间
We may need more than a week.
你们知道谁能立刻教好这个孩子吗 瓦拉德
Hey, you know who could fix the kid in a snap? Vlad.
什么 我们不需要瓦拉德 我们能解决
What? We don't need to call Vlad. We got this.
你知道吗 丹尼索维奇 怪物都像你一样那么友善
You see, Denisovich, monsters are nice, just like you.
但是当月亮升起后 真正的怪物娱乐才开始
But when the moon comes out, the real monster fun begins.
变得可怕起来 对吧 朋友们
Being scary. Right, guys?
伙计 伙计们 你们有毛病吗
Guys? Guys! What is wrong with you?
拜托 大家都爱那首歌
Come on. Everybody likes that song.
我们不是普通人 我们是可怕的怪物 记得吗
We're not everybody. We're scary monsters. Remember?
你把什么放进去了
Hey, what are you putting in?
有声读物
It's an audio book.
大脚怪的生平事迹 他亲口述说
Bigfoot's life story. He reads it himself.
第一章
Chapter one.
这次旅行肯定很精彩
This is gonna be so amazing.
是啊 你会玩得很高兴的 但别太高兴了
Oh, yeah. You're gonna be so happy, but not too happy.
- 什么 - 没什么
- Huh? - What?
我想看看你成长中的每一个地方
I wanna see everything you did growing up.
只要让你分心就好 明白吗
As long as you're distracted, capisce?
去我父母那里的途中我们可以去几个地方
We can hit a few spots on the way to my parents.
我先给家里打个电话
Lemme just quickly call home.
别打
Ah! Don't do that.
那边是凌晨一点呢 丹尼斯还没起床
It's only 1:00 A.M. there. Dennis isn't even up yet.
对哦 我只是不习惯他不在身边
Right. I'm just not used to being away from him.
一切都没事的 你爸爸能照顾好一切
Everything's gonna be cool. Your Dad was so all over it.
我明白 他是最棒的
I know. He's the best.
这里右转
Right turn, here.
丹尼索维奇 起床了
Denisovich, rise and shine.
伙计们 这让你们想起什么了吗
Boys, this bringing back any memories?
我们一百岁的时候常常在这一带晃悠
We used to prowl around here when we were in our 100s.
斯洛博齐亚的黑暗森林
The dark forest of Slobozia.
真美 他们怎么建的啊
Nice how they built it up.
好吧 下车
Okay, out of the car.
丹尼索维奇 你会发现
Denisovich, you're going to see
每个怪物都有他的特殊之处
every monster do his specialty.
首先 弗兰克会给我们展示他是怎么吓人的
First, Frank's gonna show us how he scares people.
耶 他会说 嘣
Yay! He's gonna say, "boo."
我不觉得"嘣"能吓到人
Yeah, I don't think "boos" ever work.
但这就是我们来这里的原因 向大师学习
But that's why we're here. To learn from the master.
好吧 我试试看
Okay, I'll give it a shot.
我猜这取决于工作
Yeah, guess it just depends on work.
科学怪人
Frankenstein!
嘿 你们好吗
Hey, how ya doin'?
你太帅了 我们能合照一张吗 可以吗
You're awesome! Can we take a picture? Is that okay?
当然可以 先摆个自拍造型
Sure, okay. Little selfie action.
不是吧
For real?
太棒啦 非常谢谢你
Awesome! Thank you so much.
祝你们有个愉快的一天
Hey, have a great day.
嘣
Boo!
他真可爱 太可爱了
Oh. He's adorable. He's adorable.
可爱 好吧
Adorable, yes.
不吓人 但至少"嘣"是个开始
Not scary, but "boo" is a start.
我的生日蛋糕上面要有最酷的人
My birthday cake's gonna have the coolest guy on it.
让我猜猜 是凯蒂
Let me guess. Kakie.
不 他超级酷 他能爬墙 还穿着披风
No. He's so cool. He climbs walls and wears a cape.
真的吗 那这个最酷的人是谁
Oh, really. And who is this very cool guy?
蝙蝠侠
Batman!
蝙蝠侠 好吧
Batman. Great.
你就不认识其他穿披风又很酷的人吗
You don't know anyone else with a cape that's cool?
这里不错 停下
This is good. Stop here.
好了 韦恩 该你了 去杀点东西
Okay, Wayne. It's your turn. Go kill something.
丹尼索维奇 看好了
Denisovich, watch this.
什么
What?
我跟你说过的 来吧
I told you, come on.
如果我们不启迪丹尼索维奇
If we don't inspire Denisovich,
他怎么发现他内心的怪物啊
how's he going to find his inner monster?
谁在怪物里面
Who's in a monster?
没人 只是…
Nobody, just...
来 吃个牛油果吧
Here, have an avocado.
你妈咪说这是健康脂肪
Your mommy says it's a good fat.
我也不知道这是什么意思
Whatever the heaven that means.
听着 我不会为了让你外孙有个吸血鬼的样子
Listen, I'm not gonna set monsters back again
就变回原来的怪物
just to make your grandkid like vampires.
再说了 这里也没什么可杀的 都是…
Anyway, there's nothing to kill here. It's all been...
真可爱
What a cutie.
但还是要杀了它
But kill him.
真是棒啊 你知道我好几年没这样干了
Oh, great. You know I haven't done this in years.
我们没必要杀任何东西了 我们有汽水蛋挞
We don't need to kill anymore. We have pop-tarts.
丹尼索维奇 你会爱上这个的
Denisovich, you're going to love this.
韦恩会吃掉整只鹿 下一只就是你的
Wayne's going to eat that whole deer, and the next one's yours.
韦恩 上
Wayne, go.
老天啊 我真是太老了
Oh, man. I'm too old for this.
好吧 是怎么叫的啊
Okay, how's it go again?
不不 等等 那是满月时候的叫声
No, no, wait. That's for the moon.
我该咆哮的 对 就是这样
Oh, I growl. Right, here goes.
咆哮
Growl!
接住它 好孩子
Get it, boy.
加油 韦恩叔叔
Get it, uncle Wayne.
某狼人 你刚刚真的把"咆哮"俩字说出来了吗
Some werewolf. Did you actually say the word "growl?"
你真是个懦弱鬼
You're a werewussy.
我说过我生疏了
I said I was rusty.
把飞盘给我
Gimme me that frisbee.
不 这是我的飞盘 我接住的
No! It's my frisbee! I fetched it!
给我 给我
Give it to me! Give it back!
- 拿过来 给我 - 还给我
- Give it over here! Give me that! - Give it back!
他没事的 他可是鼻涕虫
He's fine. He's Blobby.
这地方太漂亮了
This place is so amazing and scenic.
你首先带我去看什么
What do you wanna show me first?
我不知道
Mmm. I don't know.
是很漂亮 但这里天黑以后
It's pretty, but there's really
就真的没什么可做的
nothing to do once it gets dark.
等等 这是什么地方
Wait. What's that place?
所以 你是说我可以在
So, you're telling me that I can pick
所有口味的薯片任意挑选吗
between all these different kinds of chips?
是的
Yes.
人们该如何抉择啊
How do people decide?
那个漂亮的红宝石喷泉是什么啊
Now what's that beautiful fountain of rubies?
乔尼 你有喝过这个思乐冰饮料吗
Johnny, have you tried this slurpee?
别喝那么快 亲爱的
Not that quickly, hon.
它有四十八种口味 我们把它们尝个遍吧
It comes in 48 flavors. We have to try them all.
我不知道我们时间够不够
Uh, I don't know if we have time.
为什么 这个地方整晚都在营业 对吧 先生
Why? This place is open all night. Right, sir?
是的
Yes.
乔尼 快看
Johnny, look.
他们在这个地方拍电视节目 而我们是明星
They're making a TV show about this place and we're the stars.
世界各地的朋友们 你们好啊
Hello, world.
棒极了
Awesome.
真的太棒了 你太幸运了 卡尔
It's totally awesome. You're so lucky, Kal.
朋友们大家好
Hello, world.
好了 墨瑞 该你了
Okay, Murray. Your turn.
打扰了 你知道这附近哪里可以被咬吗
Excuse us. Do you know where someone can get a bite around here?
你真的要问一只吸血鬼哪里可以提供咬人服务吗
Did you seriously just ask a vampire where to get a bite?
天呐 我不是那个意思 我们不是这里的人
Oh, gosh. I didn't mean... We're not from around here.
太尴尬了 赶紧开车吧
This is so embarrassing. Just keep going.
抱歉打扰你了 我喜欢你的巧克力麦片哟
Sorry to bother you. Love your chocolate cereal.
所以 你现在想让我干什么
So, what do you want me to do now?
丹尼索维奇 你肯定不会相信
Denisovich, you won't believe it.
木乃伊可以破墙而入
The mummy can crash through walls
然后变成一大堆的甲壳虫
and turn into a swarm of beetles
还可以诅咒任何人
and put a curse on anyone.
听起来好可怕哦
That sounds mean.
是有趣的可怕 好了
It's fun mean. Okay.
看好了
So, check it out.
墨瑞会用魔法召唤出你从未见过的最大的沙尘暴
Murray's going to conjure up the biggest sandstorm you've ever seen.
来吧
Hit it!
沙尘暴 好久没试过了
Sandstorm? It's been awhile.
我不管 赶紧的 咒语念起来
Not my problem. Do it. Say your little spell.
好吧
Okay.
我开始了 弗兰克 韦恩 格里芬 小心别被吓晕了
I got this. Frank, Wayne, Griffin, just try not to faint.
嗷
Ow!
闪到背了
My back.
等等
Oh.Wait.
多可爱啊
How cute!
等等 在运动场边停车 看看那些可爱的孩子们啊
Wait. Stop at that playground. Look at these cute kids.
我的天啊 这看上去简直酷到爆
Holy rabies! This looks like a blast.
我不知道 小梅
I don't know, Mavey.
如果你不知道怎么做的话 这项运动很危险的
This can be pretty dangerous if you don't know what you're doing.
当然啦 我骑这个小意思
Of course, I rock these bikes.
我能借用你的车吗 小兄弟
May I, little dude?
看好了
Check it out. Oh, yeah.
我每个暑假都会这么骑
This is how I rolled every summer.
我觉得我把它刮坏了
I think I scratched it.
该我啦
My turn.
小梅 我说过了 我花了好多年才练得这么棒的
Mavey, I told you, it took me years to get this good.
好吧 我会试试看
Well, I'll give it a try.
看到了吧 这就是我的女朋友 渣渣们
You feel me now? That's my girlfriend, suckers.
是你老婆乔尼
Your wife, Johnny.
我老婆 这更棒
My wife. Even better.
太厉害了 姐姐 你是从哪里学到的啊
That was sick, lady. Where did you learn how to do that stuff?
特兰西瓦尼亚
Transylvania.
酷 我有个表兄是从宾夕法尼亚州来的
That's cool. I have a cousin from Pennsylvania.
这些小孩子太可爱了 丹尼斯肯定会喜欢他们的
Oh. These little guys are so sweet. Dennis would love them.
这地方太适合抚养孩子了
What an awesome place to raise a kid.
抚养孩子
Oh. To raise a kid?
我不确定是否合适
I don't know about awesome.
可能会被欺负 明白吗
Maybe tubular. Capisce?
不管怎样 我们该去我家里看看
Anyways, we should hit my folks' place.
我跟他们说我们马上就到
I said we'd be there by now.
当然
Sure.
现在特兰西瓦尼亚那边已经过三点了
Oh, hey, it's after 3:00 in Transylvania.
我打电话去看看丹尼斯怎么样了 好吗
I'm gonna check on Dennis, okay?
巧克力麦片 你在逗我吗
Chocolate cereal. Are you kidding me?
没关系的 德古 那是因为人们爱我们
It's okay, Drac. It's 'cause they love us.
是啊 怪物们现在是潮流
Yeah. Monsters are what's goin' on.
对啊 你应该像我一样接受这个事实
Oh, yeah. You should embrace it like I did.
我有一个超级畅销的健身教学
I've got a best-selling workout video.
跟我做 女士们 右边 左边
Follow me, ladies. Right. And left.
不对 女孩们 看着我 你根本没有注意看
No, girls. Watch me. You're not watching.
开始了 八 七 六
Here we go. And eight and seven and six...
我才不是那种人 伙计们
That's not me, guys.
拜托 就连大脚怪都在德国的足球联赛里大显身手了
Come on, even bigfoot's tearin' it up in the German soccer league.
噢 不 不不不
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no.
是梅菲丝
It's Mavis.
你得接啊
You gotta answer it.
你按得太用力了 轻点
You're pushin' too hard. Lighter.
知道了
All right!
丹尼索维奇 醒醒 天呐 他睡死了
Denisovich, wake up. Oh, boy, he's out cold.
看我的
I got this.
爸爸 怎么这么久才接电话
Dad, what took so long?
什么
What?
没什么 小梅 我们在旅社里一切都好
Nothing, Mavey. We're all great here at the hotel.
在做旅馆里的事情
Just doing hotel things.
不好意思 控制下你的呼吸好吗
Sorry, can't handle your breath.
好吧
I hear ya.
你怎么样
How are you?
我们玩得超开心
We're having a blast.
我们去骑了车 还去了迷你超市 这儿太有意思了
We just went biking and mini-marting. It's so fun here.
丹尼斯还好吧
Is Dennis okay?
当然了
Oh. Of course.
想见见他吗
You want to see him?
想啊
Yes. Yes, I do.
宝贝 你还好吗
Hi, baby. How are you?
妈咪
Mommy.
我很开心
I happy.
嘿 小家伙
Hey, little dude.
他为什么戴着墨镜
Why is he wearing sunglasses?
我们在玩耍呢
Oh, we were playing.
扮演超级英雄
It's a superhero thing.
为因 我是墨镜侠 要拯救世界
Cebause, I'm sunglasses man, to the rescue!
- 好了 别演太过了 - 我在飞哦
- Okay, take it down a notch. - I'm flying.
你的声音很奇怪
You sound funny.
不不 那是他在假装墨镜侠的声音
Oh, no, no, that's his sunglasses man voice.
有干扰 信号好差 梅菲丝 你还在吗
Static. The signal is bad. Mavis, are you there?
我还…
Yeah, I'm still...
好吧 看来他正玩得开心
All right. I guess he's having fun.
当然了
Of course he is.
哇 我用墨镜侠摆平了问题
Wow, I nailed it with the sunglasses man.
这是我所能想到的最好办法
Right off the top of my head.
我刚才说了一个" 为因" 有人注意到了吗
I threw in a "cebause." Did everyone see that?
她说她玩得很开心乔尼搞砸了
She said she was having fun. Johnny's blowing it.
她骑了车还逛了迷你超市 她要搬走了
She's biking and mini-marting. She's gonna wanna move!
我得马上把这小鬼搞定 我们是不是快到了
I gotta fix this kid now. Are we almost there or what?
好吧 我可能
Okay, I may
在几英里前走错方向了
have taken a wrong turn a few miles back.
- 别生气 - 什么
- Don't get mad. - What?
谁来把这玩意儿的导航打开
Someone turn on the navigator on this thing.
看我按得多轻柔
Look how light I touch it.
请输入你的目的地
Please enter your destination.
拜托 我求求你了
Please. I am begging you.
会没事的 丹尼索维奇
Yeah, this is gonna be good, Denisovich.
可怕的东西 就在你的内心里
Scary stuff, okay? It's in you.
我们只需要集中注意力到可怕的事上
We just gotta concentrate on the scary.
德古外公 你想念外婆吗
Papa Drac? Do you miss Grandma?
想念外婆 当然了
Miss Grandma? Oh. Sure, I do.
我每天都想 她是我的命中注定
I miss her every day. She was my zing.
为什么这么问
Why do you ask?
我不知道
I don't know.
那你有想念谁吗
Do you miss anybody?
我想妈妈和爸爸
I miss mommy and Daddy.
还有呢 你想温妮吗
And who else? You miss that Winnie?
就是那只每天扑你又舔你的小狼崽
The pup who tackles you and tries to lick you all the time?
想啊 但我们只是朋友而已
Yeah, but we're just friends.
不不 你是个吸血鬼
Oh, no, no, no. You're a Dracula.
你不能和像温妮这样毛绒绒的小可爱做朋友
You can't just be friends with a cute, hairy number like Winnie.
现在右转 你这个蠢货
Right turn, now! Here. You imbecile!
右边 转吧 格里芬
Oh, right. Turn, Griffin!
遵命 德古外公
Yes, Papa Drac.
等着瞧 伙计们 这小鬼马上就会畅饮山羊血了
Wait and see, fellas. This kid'll be guzzling goat blood in no time.
你已到达目的地了 耶
You have arrived at your destination. Yes!
我们到咯
Yes! Here we are.
这是我小时候来过的吸血鬼夏令营
It's the vampire summer camp I went to as a kid.
什么东西 吸血营吗？
What's it, camp vamp?
不 谁会起"吸血营"这种名字
No. Who names their camp "camp vamp?"
是怪物速成特训营
It's camp Winnepacaca.
瞧见没 丹尼索维奇
You see, Denisovich?
这就是教会我变身和抓老鼠的地方
This is where I learned to catch mice and shapeshift.
以及如何使用我那些神奇的力量 很酷吧
And use my incredible powers and strength. It's pretty cool.Huh?
羽毛球
Badminton.
对 我都不记得有羽毛球了
Yes, I don't remember this badminting.
噢 这个夜晚 还好吗 各位
Well, well, is this a night? How ya doin', folks?
我是负责人 达纳
I'm Dana, the director.
我们很荣幸能有你们这些传奇人物来拜访
We're sure excited to have you legends visitin' us.
我能为你们做些什么
What can I do you for?
我想把我的孙子丹尼索维奇 送到这儿来
Well, I'm very interested in sending my grandboy, Denisovich, here.
就是这个头发红红没有獠牙的小家伙吗
Oh. This little redheaded, non-fangy little guy?
噢 他会有的 只是长得慢 所以我们才来这儿了
Oh, they're in there. He's a late fanger. That's why we came here.
可以给我们看些训练吗
Can you show us some of the drills,
比如他们抓老鼠的地方
like where they catch the mice?
可以 不过现在我们称它为"立竿拿鼠"
Can do. A-course now we call it Tee-mousing.
所以他们不用跑去捉老鼠咯
So they don't have to catch the mice?
不用 我们发现这样更能增强他们的自信心
Nope. We find this is a good way to build their confidence.
过来
Come here.
它就在这儿啊 你怎么搞的
It's right there! What's the matter with you?
小戏法而已
Hokey-pokey.
就是这里 丹尼索维奇 外公学会飞行的地方
There it is, Denisovich. Where Papa learned to fly.
我也想像外公一样飞翔
Ooh! I wanna fly like Papa.
我们现在换成那种了
Yeah. We're over here, now.
得把高度降低 确保安全
Had to scale it down. Insurance.
救我 救我
Help me. Help me. Help me.
小戏法 营火堆见
Hokey-pokey. See ya at the campfire.
天啊 欢迎你们俩个
Well, gosh! Welcome, you two.
好啊 各位
Hey, gang.
嘿 真是太激动了
Hi, guys. This is so exciting.
看看这些 太酷了
Ah! Look at all of this. So cool.
不敢相信我真的来到这了
Wow! I can't believe I'm actually here.
你确实来了
Well, you are.
现在该怎么安排呢 你要晚上熬夜白天睡觉吗
Now, how does it work? Are you up all night and sleep all day?
对啊
Yeah.
你们想我怎样做我就怎么做
Oh. I'll do whatever you guys want.
很好
Good.
- 我买了这个太阳帽给你 - 琳达
- 'Cause I bought this pretty sunhat for you. - Linda.
还有这个斗篷 如果你想确保安全的话
But otherwise this poncho, if you wanna be safe.
我们可以一会儿再说这个 琳达
We can deal with it later, Linda.
好吧
Okay.
噢 过来看啊
Oh! Come see.
我给你们布置好了卧室
I've set up your bedroom.
和特兰西瓦尼亚精灵旅社一样
It's just like Transylvania.
特兰西瓦尼亚 那是段很有趣的经历
Oh, Transylvania. That was a fun experience.
迈克还很怕他会被开肠破肚或被吃掉
Mike was afraid he'd get disemboweled and eaten,
但我告诉他 他是在犯傻
but I told him he was just being silly.
明明是你 琳达
That was you, Linda.
噢 他们到了
Oh. There they are.
你知道吗 我们周围有几对组合家庭
You know, we have a couple of mixed families in the neighborhood,
所以我就想着邀请他们过来
so I thought I'd invite them over.
既然你在考虑要不要搬过来
They might be nice for you guys to talk to
和他们聊聊或许对你们有帮助
since you're thinkin' about moving here.
嗨 卡伦 嗨 潘德果拉
Hi, Caren. Hi, Pandragora.
- 欢迎你 梅菲丝 - 大家好啊
- Welcome, Mavis. - Hey, guys.
你会很快融入这里的 用不着担心
Yeah, you're gonna dig it here. Don't even worry.
大家对我们的生活方式完全没意见
People are totally cool with our lifestyle choice.
虽然孩子们有时候会受点欺负
I mean, the kids get picked on a little,
但这会让他们变得更加坚强
but it toughens them up.
噢 你们好 这是洛蕾塔
Oh, hey, you guys. And this is Loretta.
她嫁给了保罗 他是个狼人
She's married to Paul, who's a werewolf.
什么
Excuse me?
我正向梅菲丝介绍城里其他人类和怪物组合的家庭
Yes, I was telling Mavis about the other monster-human couples in town.
我不是狼人
I am not a werewolf.
我还以为…
Oh. I thought...
那欢迎你留下来吃点蛋糕
Well, you're welcome to stay and have some cupcakes.
吸血鬼们永远都是好朋友
∮ Vampires will be friends forever ∮
一起走过了无数个世纪
∮ Through the centuries together ∮
即使是在最毒辣的太阳下
∮ Even in the brightest sunny weather ∮
吸血鬼们也会是永远的朋友
∮ Vampires will be friends forever ∮
真正意义上的
∮ Literally ∮
永远
∮ Forever ∮
唱的好 小吸血鬼们 抱抱自己吧
great job, vampires. Give yourselves a hug.
我们得走了
We're going.
什么 去哪
What? Where?
我们爬上去干嘛
Why are we doing this?
难道你想去听那些烂歌吗
You'd rather be listening to those putrid new songs?
那个在岸边啃尸体的米迦勒去哪了
What happened to Michael row your corpse ashore?
还有那个拿着斧头的狼人呢
Or old mcwerewolf had an axe?
我们不该上来的 德古
We shouldn't be up here, Drac.
谁准备飞飞了呀
Who's ready to fly?
我 就像超级英雄一样
Me! Me! Like a superhero.
更好 像吸血鬼一样
Better! Like a vampire!
这塔快散架了
This thing is rickety.
你知道吗 也许这小鬼不该去飞
You know what? Maybe the kid isn't supposed to fly.
闭嘴 这才是学习的最好方法 把他们扔出去后自然就学会了
Quiet. This is how they learn. You throw them and they figure it out.
我就是这么学会的
It's how I was taught.
我现在就想飞
I wanna fly now!
小调皮 你要知道外公会一直在你身边
Attabat. You know Papa's right here if you need him.
我不敢看这个
Uh. I can't watch this.
不要这样子
Please don't.
要飞咯
Here we go!
他还没飞起来
He's still not flying.
他会的
He will.
还是没有
Still not.
会飞的
It'll happen.
这塔真高
This is a tall tower.
所以才选这里
That's why it's good.
你该去接他了
You should get him.
他会摔死的
He's gonna fall to his death.
他正在慢慢学习
He's taking his time.
德古
Drac!
我第一次也这样
I did that my first time.
他快要接近地面了
He's getting too close to the ground!
你知道吗 他是不会飞起来了
You know what? He's not gonna fly.
我说过 外公一直都在你身边
I told you. Papa's always here for you.
再来 再来
Again! Again!
我的老天 我们必须上报这件事
Oh, dear. Oh, my devil. We're gonna have to report this.
你是说上报纸吗
You mean to the papers?
虽然那样很酷 但我是不会接受采访的
I guess it was pretty cool, but I'm not about getting press.
不 先生 我是说上报给当局
No, sir. I mean the authorities.
我不能包庇你伤害儿童的行为
I can't not report child endangerment.
听我说 那只是好玩
Whoa! Listen to me. That was fun.
你的歌才是伤害儿童
Your singing is child endangerment.
我们要下去帮他吗
Should we go down and help him?
不 我都说了这样不对 他得靠自己
Nope. I told him this was nuts. He's on his own.
我们得打电话给小孩的母亲
We have to call the boy's mother.
不 这可不行
No, that ain't happening.
他妈妈已经疯咯
His mother's already nutsy koo koo!
我得遵守规定
I have to follow protocol.
你不能遵守规定
You will not follow protocol.
我是吸血鬼 我才不会被催眠
I'm a vampire. I can't be hypnotized.
好吧
Right.
拜托 别逼我打电话报警
Now, please. Don't make me call the police.
谁也不准打电话
No one's calling nobody!
着火啦
Fire!
停下 然后躺下来滚滚
Stop, drop and roll. Stop, drop and roll.
尖叫是没用的
Screaming's not helping!
我们是坏人吗 德古外公
Are we bad guys, Papa Drac?
坏人？
Bad?
不 你是世界上最好的小孩
No. You're the best kid in the world.
不是我们放的火 是那座塔
We didn't start the fire. It was the tower.
那座塔十分危险 你应该庆幸我们没有上报给当局
That's a very unsafe tower. You're lucky we don't call the authorities.
走吧 我的小英雄
Let's go, my hero.
因为我是蝙蝠侠 去坐蝙蝠车吧
Cebause I'm Batman! To the Batmobile!
对 去坐…
Yes. To the...
很抱歉刚才的事 他们也许觉得你会喜欢吧
Sorry about all that stuff. I guess they thought you'd like it.
为什么我感觉自己在这像个怪胎
Why do I feel so weird here?
不 亲爱的 是他们太怪异了
No, hon. They're being weird.
我觉得他们只是想帮我
I think they're just trying to help me.
我是说 从小我就在旅馆里长大 对于外界我一无所知
I mean, I grew up knowing nothing living inside that hotel.
而你对圣诞老人却了如指掌
And you learned about everything growing up in Santa Claus.
是圣克鲁斯 不过…
Santa Cruz. But, uh...
也许让丹尼斯远离精灵旅社的话
Maybe if Dennis grows up away from Transylvania,
就不会跟我一样 像个怪胎了
he won't be so freaky. Like me.
你疯了吗 梅菲丝 你简直棒呆了
Are you nuts? Mavis, you're a blast.
你对所有事情都充满了激情和好奇
You're so full of life and curious about everything.
如果丹尼斯长大像你一样
If Dennis grows up to be just like you,
那我就是世界上最幸运的父亲了
I'll be the luckiest Dad in the world.
我爱你 乔尼斯坦
I love you, Johnnystein.
你知道吗
You know what?
只要我们在一起 到哪都会很幸福
As long as we're all together, we'll be happy anywhere.
即使是在旅社
Even at the hotel.
对
Yes!
你在做什么呢
What are you doing?
快看我朋友发来的这个视频
Check out this video my friend sent me.
这小子真是天不怕地不怕
This kid is an awesome daredevil.
噢 伙计
Oh, dude!
你拍到了吗
Did you get it?
等等 那是丹尼斯吗
Wait! Is that Dennis?
不 这个看不太清楚 但是…
No! Is it? No. It's just hard to see. But...
噢 不小心删掉了 没有咯
Oops. Just deleted it. So, it's gone.
什么 是梅菲丝 我才不要接
What? It's Mavis. I'm not answering it.
接吧 德古 迟早要面对
Come on, Drac. You have to.
好吧
All right!
怎么了 小宝贝
Yes, honeybunch.
爸爸 你在哪
Dad? Where are you?
我们在旅社外面烧烤呢
Um... we're outside the hotel having a little cookout.
绝对安全
It's perfectly safe.
那是什么声音 是警笛吗
What's that noise? Is that a siren?
只是一些女妖的哀嚎声罢了
Oh, those are just some wailing banshees checking in.
安静点 女妖们
Quiet, you banshees.
我们要在这来一场绝对安全的野餐
We're trying to have a perfectly safe cookout over here.
妈妈 我想和她打个招呼 妈妈
Mommy! I wanna say hi! Mommy! Mommy!
德古外公刚刚教我怎么飞行
Papa Drac just tried to teach me how to fly.
等等 那是他母亲吗
Wait a minute. Is that the mother?
噢 又是信号问题
Oh, no. Static again.
我现在就回旅社
I am coming back to the hotel right now.
而你最好在那里 不然你绝对会后悔的
And you better be there or I swear, Dad, you're gonna be very sorry.
发生什么事了
What's goin' on?
我们得马上回去
We need to get home right away.
好吧 我去整理我的行李
Okay. I'll go wake up my backpack.
伙计们 我们得走了
Guys, we gotta move.
我们没有车 那我们要怎么走
We got no car! How we gonna get out of here?
别担心 我叫了后援
Don't worry. I made a call.
抱歉 鼻涕虫 我们本来想早点打给你的
I'm sorry, Blobby. We really meant to call you sooner.
出发
Hit it!
特兰西瓦尼亚
Transylvania.
你要去哪里
You want to go where?
特兰西瓦尼亚 越快越好
Transylvania. As soon as possible.
我们没有直飞特兰西瓦尼亚的航班
We don't fly direct to Transylvania.
没有吗
You don't?
你可以先去布加勒斯特 但是你得
You can go to Bucharest, but you'll have to
分别在芝加哥和苏黎世转机
switch planes in Chicago and then Zurich.
那我们什么时候能到
So, when would we get there?
芝加哥的航班因为天气原因而延迟
Well, the Chicago flight's delayed due to bad weather.
所以 是订两张客运汽车票吗
So, two seats in coach?
不
No!
- 不是吧 - 就是
- No! - Yes.
你非得现在去尿尿吗 我们好不容易不堵车了
You have to go now? When we finally have no traffic.
你真是要我的命 鼻涕虫
You're killing me, Blobby.
我头上还有云 得来张自拍先
I still have some cloud on me. Gotta do a selfie!
乔尼 现在不行
Johnny! Not now!
好吧 一会儿再说
Okay. Maybe later.
这个小滑轮没油了 我们永远都到不了了
This scooter thing's out of juice. We're never gonna make it.
弗兰克 吹气
Frank, blow.
就现在
Now!
好玩吗 你为什么在笑呀 你喜欢吗
How fun is this? Why are you laughing? You like that?
瞧这个
Watch this.
格叽格叽
Coochie-coochie-coochie-coo!
这就叫飞翔 丹尼索维奇
Now this is flying, Denisovich.
像吸血鬼一样
Like a vampire.
这才是我的小乖乖 看看你
That's my boy. Look at you go.
你是穿披风的人里最酷的 德古外公
You're the coolest guy who wears a cape, Papa Drac.
嘿 你什么时候才回来呀
So, hey, when are you going to get here already?
我们一直在…
We've been waiting...
把我儿子给我
Give me my son.
我们只是出去找了些鳄梨
We just went out for some avocados.
妈妈 我飞起来了
Mommy! I flew!
我看见了
I saw.
妈妈已经 疯咯
∮ Mother's already nutsy koo koo ∮
疯咯
∮ Nutsy koo koo ∮
疯咯 亲爱的
∮ Koo koo. Oh, dear. Oh, dear ∮
天呐 我得遵守规定
∮ Oh, my devil I have to follow protocol ∮
那可不行 那可不行
∮ That ain't happening that ain't happening ∮
妈妈已经
∮ Mother's already ∮
疯咯
∮ Koo koo ∮
我本来担心丹尼斯身边都是怪物会不安全
I was worried Dennis wasn't safe around other monsters.
现在我觉得他在你身边也不安全了
Now I don't even feel like he's safe around you.
但我只是…
But I was just...
你之前怎么说来着
What was it you said?
人类 怪物 还是独角兽 都无所谓
Human, monster, unicorn. That it didn't matter?
我只是觉得他的人生应该…
Well, I just know his life would...
我们周三会在这里举办他的生日派对
We'll have his birthday party here on Wednesday.
然后我们就搬走
Then we're moving.
别走 小梅 求你了
Please, Mavey. Don't leave.
也许你确实是让人类走进了你的旅社 爸爸
Maybe you've let humans into your hotel, Dad.
但我觉得你并没有让他们走进你的内心
But I don't think you've let them into your heart.
我可以做到的
I can do it. I can do it.
我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat. I'm a bat.
我是只蝙蝠 蝙蝠
I'm a bat. I'm a bat. I'm a bat!
丹尼斯 你在干什么 亲爱的
Dennis? What are you doing, sweetie?
没什么
Uh... nothing.
小心 我帮你下来吧
Careful. Let me help you down from there.
你期待你的生日派对吗
Are you getting excited about your big party?
我想是吧
I guess so.
你知道谁会来吗 爸爸的整个家庭
You know who's coming? Daddy's whole family.
迈克爷爷和琳达奶奶
Grandpa Mike and Grandma Linda.
所有那些爱你的表亲 姑姑 叔叔
All your cousins and aunts and uncles who love you so much.
然后 我们会搬到加利福尼亚州和他们一起住的
And then they're gonna be with us when we move to California.
妈咪 是不是因为我不是怪物我们才要搬走的
Mommy, are we going away cebause I'm not a monster?
什么 不 丹尼斯 当然不是了
What? No. Dennis, of course not.
这只是成长的烦恼
It's just grown-up stuff.
好吧 但是德古外公呢
Okay. But what about Papa Drac?
他只能孤单待在这里了
He's gonna be here all alone.
德古外公得待在这里打理旅社
Papa Drac has to stay here to run the hotel.
不过他会来探望我们的 我们也会来探望他
But he'll visit us. And we'll visit him.
我们能不能每天晚上都跟他通电话
Can we call him every night?
当然了
Sure.
真棒
Awesome!
你好 我们来了
Hello. We're here.
今晚乔尼的家人齐聚在此
∮ The night brings Johnny's family here ∮
要带走德古所珍视的一切
∮ To take away all that Drac holds dear? ∮
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome, welcome.
隐藏你的感情
∮ Hide your feelings ∮
不要宣泄出来
∮ Keep them all inside ∮
伙计 为什么你要走 这地方酷毙了
Dude, why do you wanna leave? This place is out of control.
我不想走
I don't wanna leave.
这些了不起的怪家伙
All these awesome freakazoids!
谁才是最酷的怪物
So, who's the coolest monster?
凯蒂
Kakie.
凯蒂 你真是个胆小鬼
Kakie. What a wussbag.
难道全家聚在一起不好吗
Isn't it nice to have the whole family together?
梅菲丝 你们家有表兄妹什么的吗
Mavis, do you have any cousins or thingies in your family?
没有 只有我和爸爸
No. It's just been me and Dad.
我从来没问过你是怎么失去你妈妈的
I never did ask how you lost your Mom.
她被愤怒的人类杀死了
Oh. She was killed by angry humans.
好尴尬
∮ Awkward ∮
不过我还有瓦拉德爷爷
but there is my Grandpa Vlad.
你有个爷爷
Oh, you have a Grandpa?
是的 他也会来参加派对的 我邀请了他
Yeah. He'll be at the party. I invited him.
你邀请了他
You invited him?
爸爸 他从没见过丹尼斯 我想走之前让他们见一面
Dad, he's never seen Dennis. I wanted them to meet once before we go.
当然了 很好 很棒 老瓦拉德
Sure. Great. Peachy. Good old Vlad.
谁有湿纸巾吗
Anybody have a wet wipe?
我的天呐 他总算邀请我了
Holy rabies. He finally invites me to something.
他有个外孙
He's got a Grandkid?
而他从来没告诉过你吗
And he never told you?
冷静点 贝拉 至少家族中又有了一个吸血鬼
Easy, Bela. At least there's another vampire in the family.
地点是间旅社吗 妙哉妙哉
It's at a hotel? Fancy schmancy.
旅社是给人类住的
Hotels are for humans!
贝拉 闭上你的臭嘴 看看你带的好头
Bela, shut your blood hole. Look what you started.
别担心 大伙们
Don't worry, gang.
我把儿子养育成了会杀戮人类并且会吸取他们的灵魂
I raised my son to hate and kill and steal the souls of humans
就像个好孩子一样
like a good boy.
是啊 瓦拉德爷爷看到我和乔尼
Yes, Grandpa Vlad will be so happy
安排的这场大型假面派对一定会非常高兴的
when he sees the big masquerade party Johnny and I have planned.
什么
What?
合作点 那是我爸爸
Play along. It's my Dad.
你有爸爸 真有趣
You have a Dad? That's funny.
听我说 绝不能让我爸爸知道你是人类
Listen to me. My Dad cannot know you're a human.
还有你家人
Or any of your family.
什么 但是 德古 我很骄傲我们是…
What? But, Drac, I'm proud that we're...
否则他会吸取你家人的灵魂 再吃掉你的背包
Or he'll steal your family's souls and eat your backpack.
正是如此 伙计们
That's right, gang.
我们要把生日会办成怪物假面派对
We're gonna make the birthday a monster masquerade party.
- 真的吗 - 太可爱了
- Really? - Oh, that's lovely.
是在丹尼斯回归正常人之前的最后的狂欢吧
Sort of like a last hurrah before Dennis gets to be with normal people.
你说得再好不过了
I couldn't have said it better.
你觉得如何 梅菲丝
What do you think, Mavis?
我觉得自己开始喜欢上令人毛骨悚然的样子了
I think I'm starting to like being creepy.
你应该庆幸我们没有上报给当局
You're lucky we don't call the authorities.
走吧 我的小英雄
Let's go, my hero.
因为我就是蝙蝠侠
Cebause I'm Batman!
好耶 去开蝙蝠车
Yes! To the Batmobile!
你被一个小女孩欺负了 蝙蝠侠
Got your butt kicked by a girl, Batman.
随便啦 我不会哭的
Yeah. Whatever. I'm not about to cry.
精灵旅社
Hotel Transylvania.
我闻到人类的味道了
I smell humans!
拆了它吧
Tear it down!
贝拉 我们在外面的世界 你总会闻到人类的气息的
Bela, we're in the outside world. You're gonna smell humans.
你知道吗 待在外面等我 这是家庭聚会
You know what? Just wait outside for me. This is family stuff.
你只会碍手碍脚
You'll only get in the way.
我要去见见小尖牙了
I just wanna meet the little fanger.
他应该认识他的吸血尊上（曾吸血外公）
He should know his great-vampa.
他的什么
His what?
曾吸血鬼外公 得了吧 这么明显的事
Vampire Grandpa. Come on. That was obvious.
很棒的派对
Amazing party!
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
这就是你的吸血鬼服装吗 你干嘛 疯了吗
This is your vampire costume? What are you, nuts?
我在网上订的
I ordered it online.
是唯一能连夜送货的地方
It was the only place that delivered overnight.
你看起来就像在脑袋上顶了个狒狒的屁股
You look like you got a baboon's butt on your head.
你至少练习了下嗓音吧
Have you at least practiced your voice?
你可不能像个嬉皮士一样说话
You can't just talk like a hippie.
我不是嬉皮士 我是街头浪人
I'm not a hippie. I'm a slacker.
像吸血鬼一样说话
Talk like a vampire.
我叫乔纳方伯爵 我是个吸血鬼
My name is Count Jonafang. I am a vampire.
吸血鬼不会到处去说 "我是个吸血鬼"
Okay, vampires don't go around saying, "I am a vampire."
不好意思 我是乔纳方伯爵 巴拉巴拉
Sorry. I am Count Jonafang. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
你在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
对不起 我紧张了
I'm sorry. I'm nervous.
听着 如果你觉得我都不喜欢
Yeah, listen, if you think I don't like it,
你绝对不会想
you definitely don't want to say,
在我父亲面前说 "巴拉巴拉"
"bleh, bleh-bleh, " in front of my father.
先生 凯蒂大师到了
Sir, Master Kakie has arrived.
德古 这位是布兰登 也就是凯蒂
Drac, this is Brandon, A.K.A. Kakie.
- 我们为了丹尼斯把他请来的 - 你好 伙计
- We got him for Dennis. - Hey, man.
见到你真想吐
Nauseated to meet you.
要搞到什么时候 我半个小时后还要赶一场书展
When does this happen? I got a book fair in half an hour.
好吧 我的吸血鬼儿子呢
All right. Where's my vampson?
拜托 什么时候了还在搞戏剧化入场
Oh, please. Still has to make a dramatic entrance.
爸爸 你看你
Dad! Look at you!
所以你现在是经营旅社吗
So you run a hotel now?
从黑暗王子变成了客房服务之王
From prince of darkness to king of room service.
是啊 很高兴见到你
Yes. So good to see you.
我马上就过来陪你
I'll be right with you.
让瓦拉德远离人类和梅菲丝
Keep Vlad away from the humans and Mavis.
马上去办
I'm on it.
这个服装才叫有型呢
Oh, now that is a neat costume.
这两个人闻起来怪怪的
These two smell funny.
你是欧洲人
Oh, you're European.
这个叫做除臭剂
It's called deodorant.
琳达 羞辱一整个洲真是无与伦比的感觉
Nothing like insulting an entire continent, Linda.
伯爵 近况如何 我是科学怪人
Hey, count! How goes it? Frankenstein.
准确的说 我是弗兰肯斯坦创造出来的怪物
Actually, I'm technically Frankenstein's monster.
弗兰肯斯坦 他是个博士…
Frankenstein, he's the doctor who...
我真想再听多点 电话预约我吧
Would love to hear more. Call my people.
我来为你介绍你儿子的其他朋友吧
So, let me introduce you to some of your son's other buddies.
这位是墨瑞
This is Murray.
求你不要杀我
Please don't kill me!
我是说 哟 老鬼 有何贵干
I mean, yo, v! What's up?
会说话的厕纸 是个新品种
Talking toilet paper. Well, that's a new one.
好吧 那小孩在哪里 我想见的是他
All right! Where's the kid? That's who I wanna meet.
乔尼
Johnny!
这位是德古拉的女婿
This is Dracula's son-in-law.
我是乔纳方伯爵
I am Count Jonafang.
巴拉巴拉 黑羊
Bleh, bleh, black sheep.
你有羊毛吗
Have you any wool?
你头上那个是什么玩意
What's that thing on your head?
看起来像我奶奶的胸部
Looks like my Grandmother's boobies.
爹地 那个脸长得怪怪的人是谁
Daddy, who's the man with the funny face?
这就是那孩子吗
Is this the kid?
肯定是了
It sure is.
让我看看那些尖牙
Let me see those fangs.
你在干什么
What are you doin'?
我只是太爱他了
Oh, I just love him so much.
我要把他所有的尖牙统统抱在怀里
I want to hug him right in the fangs that he has.
我再说一次 让我看看尖牙
I repeat, lemme see those fangs.
噢 他出牙出的晚 跟你一样
Oh, he's a late fanger, just like you.
对 就像我一样
Yes. Yes. Just like me.
这位大人物曾经也是个爱哭的宝宝 对吧
The big shot here was a little crybaby, all right.
对 我以前是
Yes, yes, I was.
还曾经尿过床
Used to pee in his bed.
好了 爸爸
Okay, Dad.
我们只需要把那孩子吓出尖牙来
We just need to scare the fangs out of the kid.
吓出尖牙来
Hare ha hangs?
对 过去我就是这么对眼前这位硬汉干的
Yeah, it's what I did for Mr. tough guy here.
首先 你要用魔法控制住
First, you've got to possess something
那个晚出牙孩子觉得天真无邪的东西
the late fanger finds sweet and innocent.
然后你就给他们如此展示 接着…
Then you show them what's what and...
嘣
Pop!
相信我 马上就可以把尖牙都吓出来 对吧 德古
Trust me. It'll scare the fangs right out. Right, Drac?
说真的 先生们 如果我书展迟到的话 我会错过街头集市的
Seriously, guys, if I'm late for the book fair, I'll miss the street fair.
那就是你要找的目标
That's your guy.
魔法控制 但是丹尼斯会很伤心的
Possessed? But Dennis will be so upset.
你还没明白吗 这是咱们的机会
Don't you get it? This is our ticket.
如果在丹尼索维奇身上起作用了 嘣 他就成吸血鬼了
If it works for Denisovich, boom! He's a vampire.
那你们就都可以留下来了
And you all get to stay here.
好吧 好吧
All right. All right.
- 明白了 - 好样的
- Capisce. - Good call.
孩子们 各位请过来
Kids, everyone, have a seat.
丹尼斯为你们准备了一个大惊喜
Dennis has a big surprise for you.
独一无二的凯蒂 蛋糕怪物
The one and only Kakie, the cake monster!
孩子们好 我是凯蒂
Hey, kids! It's me, Kakie!
多么美好的凯蒂之日
What a wonderful Kakie day it is!
现在我有个问题 这里有谁喜欢吃蛋糕吗
Now, I have a question. Who here loves cake?
升空
Rise!
为什么我在飘浮 可以叫一下舞台总监吗
Why am I floating? Can I have the stage manager, please?
这样我没法表演了
This isn't working for me.
可怕吗 丹尼索维奇 你有什么感觉了吗 起变化了吗
Scary, Denisovich? You feeling anything? Any change?
凯蒂没事吧
Is Kakie okay?
我要吃掉所有的蛋糕 分享是懦夫才会干的事
I want all the cake. Sharing is for cowards.
我可记不得电视节目里有过这段
I don't remember any of this from the TV show.
我好像在蓝光碟里看过 花絮彩蛋
Um... I think I saw it on a blu-ray disc, bonus stuff.
等等 为什么瓦拉德爷爷在那上面
Wait, why is Grandpa Vlad up there?
我好害怕 外公 凯蒂怎么了
I'm scared, Papa. What's happening to Kakie?
不是你吃蛋糕 是蛋糕要吃你
You don't eat cake. Cake eat you!
不要
No!
快停下
Stop it!
刚刚发生什么了 伙计 我要离开这里
What just happened, man? I'm outta here.
在场的家长们最好不要到网上去点评
None of these parents better review this on yelp.
你刚才在干什么呀
Hey, what did you just do?
再等多几秒钟那孩子的尖牙就能长出来了
A few more seconds and the kid's fangs would have popped right out.
我不在乎 不值得这么干
I don't care. It's not worth it.
什么不值得
What's not worth it?
这是我最后一次尝试让这孩子变成吸血鬼
It was my last attempt to make the boy a vampire,
这样你们就能留下来
so you'd stay.
通过毁掉他最喜欢的东西吗 你怎么可以这样做
By ruining his favorite thing? How could you do that?
我们只能孤注一掷了
We were desperate.
这件事你也有份吗
You were in on this?
丹尼斯在我的城市不会开心的
Dennis won't be happy in my town.
丹尼斯还从来没去过
Dennis hasn't been there.
现在这对夫妻
∮ Now husband and wife ∮
感受到了压力和冲突
∮ Feel the strain and the strife ∮
闭嘴
Shut up!
乔尼 丹尼斯不是怪物
Johnny, Dennis is not a monster.
他喜欢鳄梨
He likes avocado.
那是因为你不让他吃其他有意思的东西
'Cause you don't let him eat anything fun.
我认为丹尼斯只想成为正常人
I think Dennis just wants to be normal.
我们能不能不要用"正常"这个词
Can we stop using the word "normal"?
在我们生活的地方 他是正常的
Where we live now, he's normal.
他就是他自己 而你不能改变他 爸爸
He is who he is. And you can't change him, Dad.
丹尼斯 你要去哪里
Dennis, where are you going?
离开
Away.
但是你一个人去外面会不安全
But it's not safe out here by yourself.
我知道有个地方可以让我们躲起来 跟我来
I know a place where we can hide. Follow me.
如果刚才你没有阻止我
If you didn't stop me,
我的曾外孙就不会一辈子当个懦夫了
my great-grandson wouldn't have to be a wimp his whole life
就像这个白痴
like schlumpy over here.
- 懦夫 -乔尼 淡定
- A wimp? - Johnny, be cool.
想打一架吗 老家伙
You wanna throw down, old man?
我1997年就获得认证黄带了
Certified yellow belt since 1997.
不
No!
现在什么情况 你不是吸血鬼吗
What's this now? You're not a vampire?
巴拉
Bleh?
他当然是人类 他是我们的儿子 你觉得我们是怪物吗
Of course he's human. He's our son. You think we're monsters?
你 你让你女儿嫁个了人类 还生了个人类小孩吗
You! You let your daughter marry a human and have a human kid?
你干脆直接拿个木桩刺穿我的心脏好了
Why don't you just put a stake through my heart.
我们不再憎恨人类 人类也不再憎恨我们
We don't hate humans anymore, and they don't hate us.
人类
Humans?
你是个蠢货
You're a fool.
你的曾外孙是我见过最可爱 最善良
Your great-grandson is the sweetest, kindest,
最特别的男孩
most special boy I've ever met.
如果因为他有一半人类血统
And if you can't give him the love
你就不能给他应得的爱
he deserves because he's half-human,
那么你才是蠢货
then you're the fool.
噢 爸爸
Oh, Daddy.
丹尼斯去哪了 丹尼斯
Hey, where is Dennis? Dennis!
丹尼斯
Dennis?
生日快乐 丹尼斯 我给你做了好吃的
Happy birthday, Dennis. I made you a treat.
- 死鸽子 - 好好尝尝吧
- Dead pigeon? - Enjoy it.
因为一旦我从商学院毕业 然后开始经营自己的公司
'Cause once I graduate business school and start running a company,
你就再也享受不到这样的家常菜了
you're not gonna get home-cooked meals like this anymore.
我要搬走了 温妮 搬到加利福尼亚州
I have to move away, winnie. To California.
我妈妈觉得我在这里不开心
My mommy thinks I'm not happy here
因为我不像你一样脸上长毛
cebause I don't have hair on my face like you.
真遗憾我不是怪物
I'm sorry I'm not a monster.
不 你很完美 你是我遇到的最可爱的男生
No, you are perfect. You're the nicest boy I know.
而我有三百个兄弟呢
And I have 300 brothers.
你也很可爱 温妮
You're nice, too, winnie.
哎哟喂 人类小孩和他的宠物
Well, well, well. The little human and his pet.
- 丹尼斯 - 丹尼索维奇
- Dennis! - Denisovich!
他没在房间里
He's not in the room.
他没在泳池边
He's not by the pool.
他没在这锅汤里
He's not in this pot of soup.
他会去哪儿
Where could he be?
我真不知道为什么我会邀请你来
I don't know why I ever invited you.
丹尼斯 丹尼斯
Dennis! Dennis!
丹尼索维奇
Denisovich!
丹尼斯
Dennis!
别乱动了
Stop squirming.
为什么你要这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为这完全是个错误
Because this is wrong.
为什么就没人明白呢
Why doesn't anybody get that?
人类不该和怪物们在一起
Humans don't belong with monsters.
你才错了
You're wrong!
我没有
I am not!
我抓着你们当人质
I am holding you hostage.
我和我的兄弟们会把那间欢迎人类的旅社撕成碎片
And me and my crew are gonna tear that human-hugging hotel to shreds.
你办不到
You can't.
真的吗 为什么不行
Really? Why not?
因为…
Cebause...
因为什么
Cebause, why?
因为那会让德古外公伤心的
Cebause it will make Papa Drac sad.
伤心 那你打算怎么办呢
Ooh... sad. And what are you gonna do about it?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道为什么你不知道吗
You know why you don't know?
因为你就是个孱弱的小男孩
Cebause you're just a weak little boy.
那是什么
What was that?
丹尼斯 我们来了
Dennis, we're coming.
你没事吧 温妮
Are you okay, winnie?
是的 我的命中注定
Yes, my zing.
丹尼斯 他在那里
Dennis! There he is, right there.
丹尼斯 宝贝
Dennis! Baby!
我的好儿子
My big boy!
丹尼斯 我们到处在找你
Dennis, we were lookin' for ya.
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
找到你真是太高兴了
I'm so happy to see you.
他的坏蛋朋友来了
There's his mean friends.
噢 这下可好玩了
Oh... this'll be fun.
不是我干的
I didn't do that.
帅呆了 丹尼斯
You rock, Dennis.
他是说丹尼索维奇
He means Denisovich.
凯蒂最棒
Kakie rules!
丹尼斯 我来啦
Dennis, I'm coming. Whoa...
我就知道辛苦练习总会派上用场的
I knew all that practice would pay off.
这就对了 你们最好赶快飞走
That's right, you better fly away.
德古外公 我既是吸血鬼又是超级英雄
Papa Drac, I'm a vampire and a superhero.
我现在酷吗
Am I cool now?
"现在"吗 丹尼斯 你一直都这么酷
"Now"? Dennis, you were always cool.
无论是人类 吸血鬼 还是独角兽 你都是完美的
Human, vampire, unicorn, you're perfect no matter what.
不过既然我是吸血鬼了 我们能留下来了吗
But since I'm a vampire, can we stay here?
当然
Yes.
太好了
All right! Yeah!
All right!
不过你得知道 我们每个假期都会来这里看望你的
But you have to know, we're going to visit you here every holiday.
- 没问题 - 没问题
- That's fine. - That's fine.
再也不要靠近我或我的家人
Don't ever come near me or my family again.
不
No!
老爹 你刚刚救了一个人类
Daddy, you just saved a human.
这些压力都是因为操心
All this pressure about
这孩子的尖牙什么时候会长出来
when the boy's fangs were coming out.
谁在乎呢 我的尖牙也是前几年才长出来的 看
Who cares? Mine came out years ago! Look.
好啦 爸爸 在我们要吐之前赶快放回去吧
Okay, Dad, put 'em back in before we all barf.
嘿 今天某人的生日是不是还没有过呢
Hey! Isn't it still somebody's birthday?
让我听听你唱歌
Let me hear you sing!
不是我干的
I didn't do that.